Preliminary Inventory to the Eugene T. Rossides papers, 1969-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
Eugene T. Rossides papers
1969-1973
86045
Hoover Institution Archives
10 manuscript boxes (4.2 linear feet)
Correspondence and memoranda relating to law enforcement aspects of Treasury Department activities, including investigation of dumping of foreign goods, violations of customs laws, and the international narcotics traffic.
Rossides, Eugene T.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Assistant Secretary of the U.S. Treasury, 1969-1973.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence and memoranda relating to law enforcement aspects of Treasury Department activities, including investigation of dumping of foreign goods, violations of customs laws, and the international narcotics traffic.
United States. Dept. of the Treasury.; Customs administration--United States.; Dumping (Commercial policy); Justice, Administration of--United States.; Narcotics, Control of.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; United States--Politics and government.
- 1969 March-September (Box 1)
- 1969 October - 1970 March (Box 2)
- 1970 April-September (Box 3)
- 1970 October - 1971 February (Box 4)
- 1971 March-June (Box 5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes the following declassified records returned to file after January 2016 release by Hoover:
  Memorandum for Secretary of the Treasury John B. Connally, from Eugene T. Rossides, subject: "Recommended Letter to Secretary Rogers re Poppy Growing in Turkey," 8 April 1971.
  Memorandum for Secretary Connally, from John R. Petty and Eugene T. Rossides, attaching a proposed letter for Connally to send to Secretary of State William P. Rogers regarding the State Department's instructions to Ambassador Handley in Turkey.
  Memorandum for Secretary Connally, from Eugene T. Rossides, subject: "Turkish Opium Problem," 21 April 1971.
  Memorandum for Secretary Connally, from Eugene T. Rossides, subject: "Letters to Secretaries Rogers and Laird Regarding Recommendations for Improving Vietnamese Collections of Customs Revenue and Control of Narcotics," 21 May 1971.
  Letter from Secretary Connally to Secretary of State Rogers enclosing proposed changes to a cable of instructions to Ambassador Handley re Turkish opium negotation, 17 June 1971.
- 1971 July-November (Box 6)
- 1971 December - 1972 April (Box 7)
- 1972 May-August (Box 8)
- 1972 September-October (Box 9)
- 1972 November - 1973 January (Box 10)